Guide to the Daniel Willard Fiske papers, 1847-1927, 1847-1904 (bulk)
Fiske, Daniel Willard papers, 1847-1927, 1847-1904 (bulk)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Daniel Willard Fiske papers, 1847-1927, 1847-1903 (bulk)
13-1-1165
Willard Fiske, 1831-1904.
23.2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, scrapbooks, account books, pamphlets, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, scrapbooks, and account books pertaining chiefly to Fiske's activities as a book collector, although there are extensive family correspondence and other letters pertaining to his education, his career as a journalist, his activities as a professor and librarian at Cornell University, his interest in chess, and his cultural studies of Iceland and Egypt; included is correspondence of George Lincoln Burr, Wendell Phillips Garrison, George W. Harris, Samuel May, Charles Warner, and others.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
CHRONOLOGY
Nov. 11, 1831 Daniel Willard Fiske born at Ellisburg, New York
1845-1847 Student at Cazenovia Seminary, Cazenovia, New York
1847-1848 Student at Hamilton College, Clinton, New York
1850-1852 Scandinavia. Studied at the University of Upsala. In Copenhagen ( 1850, 1851 ), Fiske was connected with the United States Legation. Correspondent for American newspapers
1852-1861 Returned to America where he continued as newspaper correspondent. From 1852-1859, he held a position in the Astor Library (NYC). From 1857-1860, he edited the American Chess Monthly
1861-1863 Attache to the United States legation in Vienna
1863-1865 Editorial Staff of the Syracuse Daily Journal
1865-1867 Book dealer
1867-1868 Staff of the Hartford Courant
1868-1883 While traveling abroad he was offered the position of Professor of North-European Languages and Librarian of Cornell University. On July 13, 1880 he was married to Jennie McGraw who died in Ithaca on Sept. 30, 1881. During 1882-1883 Fiske made trips to Egypt and Europe and it was in the latter year that the Petrarch Collection was begun. There were more European travels until 1883 when Fiske severed all connections with Cornell University
1883-1892 Lived in Florence in a rented villa (Villa Forini) until 1888. During these years in Italy he made several trips to the United States, Egypt, Scandinavia, and other European countries.
1892-1904 In 1892 Fiske purchased and proceeded to remodel the Villa Landor near Florence where he entertained many guests and pursued his book collecting and many other interests. The Dante Collection was begun in 1893. In 1891 the Rhaeto-Romantic Collection was started.
Sept. 17, 1904 Daniel Willard Fiske died at Frankfort-on-the-Main, Germany. Buried next to Jennie McGraw Fiske in the Crypt of Sage Chapel at Cornell University.
Trips to United States were made in 1889, 1890, 1891-1892, 1893, 1895-1896, 1897; to Egypt in 1888-1889, 1898; to Scandinavia periodically (according to HSW in Chronological Outline, Willard Fiske, Life and Correspondence)
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, scrapbooks, and account books pertaining chiefly to Fiske's activities as a book collector, although there are extensive family correspondence and other letters pertaining to his education, his career as a journalist, his activities as a professor and librarian at Cornell University, his interest in chess, and his cultural studies of Iceland and Egypt; included is correspondence of George Lincoln Burr, Wendell Phillips Garrison, George W. Harris, Samuel May, Charles Warner, and others.
Additional correspondence includes instructions to Willard Austin for filing this collection in preparation for Horatio Stevens White's biography of Fiske; letters to him from acquaintances and close friends in the United States; from Italy where he spent the remainder of his years following his resignation from Cornell in 1883; from Egypt and Iceland; and from many other countries. Letters range in subject from social plans to those relating to his library and book collecting. Also, mss., fragments, notes, biographical correspondence, and post-1904 correspondence relating to the Dante and Petrarch Collections at Cornell; Egyptian manuscripts, printed material relating to the Egyptian alphabet, and photographs of Egypt; family photographs; Fiske genealogy; printed material and miscellany. Miscellaneous items include Fiske's notebooks pertaining to the Arabic language and statements of account for the the Fiske Library Fund and the Fiske Estate Library Fund; a whip, presumed to have been used by Fiske in Iceland in 1874, and an archaic lettered stone.
Also, audiocassettes of lectures on Willard Fiske given by Stephen Weissman, P.M. Mitchell, Elmer H. Antonsen, Louis Pitschmann, and Gould Colman as part of a commemoration of Fiske at Cornell University Library in 1989. These audiocassettes are cataloged individually.
Also included is a bound manuscript index of photographs (photos not included by referred to by number), annotated in French. When first received by the Cornell Library (ca. 1906?), the photographs indexed were originally assigned Harris call numbers 7851 T13-16: T13 covered Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Russia; T14, the Netherlands, Belgium, and Germany; T15, France; and T16, Italy. Also, a suitcase owned by Willard Fiske as well as a chair from his library in Florence, Italy.
INDEX TO CORRESPONDENCE
Selected correspondents, early 1870's
June 11, 1877
Adams, Charles Kendall (misfiled in 1872 folder)
1873; July 17, 1874 and others?
Bacon, Richard
Dec. 3, 1873
Behringer, George Frederick
July 25, 1872; July 28, 1873
Blair, Charles H., Zanesville
1873-1892
Boyesen, H.H., folder 11 - not interfiled
1873?
C[rane], T.F.
Mar. 7, 1874
Curtis, George William
Apr. 3, 1874; Apr. 17, 1874; Dec. 12, 1874 and earlier
D'autremont, Jr., C.
Dec. 5, 1874 and earlier
Fitch, Charles E., Roch. Dem. and Chr.
Mar. 15, 1872; Feb. 3, 1872
Folwell, William Watts
Sept. 5, 1871
Hart, James Morgan
Jan. 5, 1873
Hartford Hotel, letterhead
Feb. 8, 1873
Hartt, Ch. F., Peabody Inst.
Aug. 27, 1872; Sept. 3, 1873; Nov. 25, 1874
Hewett, Waterman Thomas [?]
1871 - exact dates?
Law, James
Dec. 19, 1872
McKoon, Bela P.
1873
Rooker, Thomas N.
Oct. 24, 1871
Russel, Wm. Channing
Dec. 1, 1873; Dec. 4, 1873; Dec. 12, 1873; Dec. 15, 1873; Jan. 1, 1874; May 11, 1874
Sanford, L[yman] G., Syracuse
Jan. 15, 1871; Jan. 15, 1873; June 2, 1873
Smith, Goldwin
May 27, 1872
Sparks, Mary C. [Mrs. Jared]
Sept. 28, 1872
White, A.D.
Selected correspondents, mid-1880's
1884
Blair, Charles H.
see separate list (green temp. cat. cd. made)
Botta, Vincenzo
1886
Burr, George Lincoln
numerous, 1880's
Evans, Edward Payson and Elizabeth E.
1884, 1885
Francis, John Morgan
Oct. 7, 1883
Fuertes, Estevan Antonio
numerous, 1880's
Garrison, Wendell Phillips
1886
Johnson, Eastman - 1 letter
Sage, Dean
1880's
Sage, Sarah Manning, Menands, Albany
1884
Schuyler, Eugene - 12 letters
1885
Schuyler, Eugene - 4 letters
1886
Schuyler, Eugene - 13 letters
1884
Stanton, Theodore - 12 letters
1886
Stanton, Theodore - 1 letter
1880's
Villari, Pasquale
Dec. 20, 1887
Wilbour, Charles E., post card from Egypt and other correspondence
SUBJECTS
Names:
Fiske, Willard, 1831-1904.; Austin, Willard, 1860-1934.; Burr, George Lincoln, 1857-1938.; Dante Alighieri, 1265-1321.; Garrison, Wendell Phillips, 1840-1907.; Harris, George William, 1849-1917.; May, Samuel, 1810-1899.; Petrarca, Francesco, 1304-1374.; Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900.; White, Horatio Stevens, 1852-1934.; Cornell University--Libraries.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Libraries. Dept. of Rare Books.; Cornell University. Libraries. Icelandic Collection.
Subjects:
Book collecting.; Chess.; Arabic language.; Book collectors.; Journalists.; Librarians.
Places:
Iceland--Description and travel.; Egypt--Description and travel.; Egypt--Description and travel--Views.; Egypt--Languages.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Audiocassettes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Includes collections #13-1-348, #13-1-1165, #13-1-1600, #13-1-28, #13-1-m896.
RELATED MATERIALS
Cf. Fiske Icelandic Collection (manuscript material, correspondence, and graphic material) Ithaca, N.Y., Cornell University Press. (Islandica 48.)
Scrapbooks of newspaper and magazine articles on virtually every subject relating to the poet Dante Alighieri and his works, 1827-1915, and correspondence dealing with Fiske's own publications and with catalogues of the Dante Collection at Cornell are housed in the Rare Book Department at Cornell.
See also the Psi Upsilon Fraternity Chi Chapter Records, #37-4-2060, for several additional letterbooks filled with Fiske correspondence mostly related to the fraternity.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Manuscripts and Notes
Series III. Petrarch Collection Material
Series IV. Dante Collection Material
Series V. Arabic Language
Series VI. Miscellaneous and Printed Material
Series VII. Photographs
Series VIII. Card files
Series IX. Audio Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Directions for Filing Fiske Material; H.S. White to Willard Austin, 1922; 1927 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Parents and Brothers, and to Joe, 1850-1868 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 2)
  - Fiske to Ettore Sordi, 1882-1904 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 3)
  - Fiske to Ettore Sordi, n.d. (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 4)
  - Letters from Fiske, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 5)
  - May Collection - correspondence and notes, 1870-1874 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 6-7)
  - May Collection - correspondence and notes, 1875-1880 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Fiske to J.M. Hart, etc., 1871-1895 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1871-1873 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Letters to FJ Garrison, December, 1874 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 12)
  - Boyesen, H.H., 1873-1892 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1874-1877 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 14-17)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1878 (Box 13-1-1165: 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1879 (Box 13-1-1165: 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence A-W, unknown, 1880 (Box 13-1-1165: 2, Folder 5-8)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1881 (Box 13-1-1165: 2, Folder 9-15)
  - Correspondence A-Y, 1882 (Box 13-1-1165: 3, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence A-W, 1883 (Box 13-1-1165: 3, Folder 8-12)
  - Correspondence A-W, unknown, 1884 (Box 13-1-1165: 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence A-W, unknown, 1885 (Box 13-1-1165: 4, Folder 6-9)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1886 (Box 13-1-1165: 4, Folder 10-12)
  - Correspondence A-W, unknown, 1887 (Box 13-1-1165: 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence A-W, 1888 (Box 13-1-1165: 5, Folder 4-6)
  - Correspondence A-W, 1889 (Box 13-1-1165: 5, Folder 7-10)
  - Correspondence A-W, 1890 (Box 13-1-1165: 6, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1891 (Box 13-1-1165: 6, Folder 6-10)
  - Correspondence A-W, unknown, 1892 (Box 13-1-1165: 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1893 (Box 13-1-1165: 7, Folder 6-11)
  - Miscellaneous Fiske, 1893-1901, n.d. (Box 13-1-1165: 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1894 (Box 13-1-1165: 8, Folder 2-8)
  - Correspondence A-W, 1895 (Box 13-1-1165: 9, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1896 (Box 13-1-1165: 9, Folder 7-11)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1897 (Box 13-1-1165: 10, Folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1898 (Box 13-1-1165: 10, Folder 6-10)
  - Correspondence A-W, 1899 (Box 13-1-1165: 11, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence A-W, unknown, 1900 (Box 13-1-1165: 11, Folder 5-9)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1901 (Box 13-1-1165: 11, Folder 10-13)
  - Correspondence A-W, 1902 (Box 13-1-1165: 12, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence A-S, 1903 (Box 13-1-1165: 12, Folder 5-8)
  - Stockwell, 1903 (Box 13-1-1165: 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence T-W, 1903 (Box 13-1-1165: 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence A-Z, 1904 (Box 13-1-1165: 13, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence A-M (Box 13-1-1165: 13, Folder 5-13)
  - Correspondence N-Z (Box 13-1-1165: 14, Folder 1-8)
  - Correspondence, unknown (Box 13-1-1165: 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, "Half-sheet updated" (Box 13-1-1165: 14, Folder 10)
  - News-clippings, Psi Upsilon announcements, invitations, etc. (Box 13-1-1165: 14, Folder 11)
  - Bibliographical correspondence, English (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 5)
  - Bibliographical correspondence, Danish, Russian, German, etc. (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 6)
  - Bibliographical correspondence, Italian (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 7)
  - Bibliographical correspondence. Notes: French Provencal, etc. (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 8)
  - Bibliographical correspondence - De Remediis (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence regarding the Fiske Collections, 1908-1918 (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1847-1848 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1849 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1850-1852 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1853-1855 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1856-1865 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1866-1870 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1871 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1872-1873 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1874-1877 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 9)
  - Postcards between Fiske and Psi Upsilon, 1876-1878 (Box 13-1-1165: 25, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1878 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Correspondence, 1879 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Correspondence, 1880 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 15-25)
  - Correspondence, 1881 (Box 13-1-348: 1, Folder 26-34)
  - Correspondence, 1881 (Box 13-1-348: 2, Folder 1-9)
  - Correspondence, 1882 (Box 13-1-348: 2, Folder 10-25)
  - Correspondence, 1883 (Box 13-1-348: 2, Folder 26-36)
  - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 13-1-348: 3, Folder 1-20)
  - Correspondence, 1885 (Box 13-1-348: 3, Folder 21-38)
  - Correspondence, 1886 (Box 13-1-348: 4, Folder 1-15)
  - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 13-1-348: 4, Folder 16-28)
  - Correspondence, 1888 (Box 13-1-348: 4, Folder 29-40)
  - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 13-1-348: 4, Folder 41-47)
  - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 13-1-348: 5, Folder 1-14)
  - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 13-1-348: 5, Folder 15-23)
  - Correspondence, 1891 (Box 13-1-348: 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 13-1-348: 6, Folder 5-16)
  - Correspondence, 1893 (Box 13-1-348: 7)
  - Correspondence, 1894 (Box 13-1-348: 8)
  - Correspondence, 1895 (Box 13-1-348: 9, Folder 1-21)
  - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 13-1-348: 9, Folder 22-29)
  - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 13-1-348: 10, Folder 1-17)
  - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 13-1-348: 10, Folder 18-28)
  - Correspondence, 1897 (Box 13-1-348: 11, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 13-1-348: 11, Folder 7-26)
  - Correspondence, 1899 (Box 13-1-348: 12, Folder 1-22)
  - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 13-1-348: 12, Folder 23-30)
  - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 13-1-348: 13, Folder 1-12)
  - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 13-1-348: 13, Folder 13-24)
  - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 13-1-348: 14, Folder 1-13)
  - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13-1-348: 14, Folder 14-24)
  - Correspondence, 1902 (Box 13-1-348: 15, Folder 1-9)
  - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 13-1-348: 15, Folder 10-20)
  - Correspondence, 1903 (Box 13-1-348: 16, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence, 1904 (Box 13-1-348: 16, Folder 7-20)
  - Fiske letters to his mother, n.d. (Box 13-1-348: 17, Folder 1-2)
    Includes letter about buying villa in Italy.
  - Correspondence: Westberg, C.F. (Box 13-1-348: 17, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 13-1-348: 17, Folder 5-12)
  - Letters from Mrs. CW Fiske to Willard Fiske, n.d. (Box 13-1-348: 17, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with George W. Burr, January 25, 1886 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence from EP Evans, February 13, 1886 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 43)
  - Letters regarding the Order of the Italian Crown, 1893 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence from M. Nijhoff, June 5, 1899 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence to HH Tyndale, August 18, 1899 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 46)
  - Harris letters, August 14, 1890 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence regarding deaths and birthdays, 1890-1910 (Box 13-1-348: 25, Folder 1-5)
  - Copied letter from Villa Landor, 1893-1901 (Box 13-1-m.896)
  - Psi Upsilon Letterbook 1875 (Box 37-4-2060: 1)
    "The correspondence in the this volume has chiefly to do with the early months of the Chi - then called the Pi - and with the efforts made to secure the legality of its existence. It supplements another volume relating to the same period of the Chi's history."
  - Psi Upsilon Letterbook 1876 Volume 1, January - June 1876 (Box 37-4-2060: 1)
    "The correspondence relates principally to the efforts to establish the Chi, to the Convention of 1876, and closes with the formal institution of the Chi in June 1876."
  - Psi Upsilon Letterbook 1876 Volume 2, July - December 1876 (Box 37-4-2060: 1)
    "The correspondence in this volume is quite miscellaneous. Some of it relates to the catalogue of 1878 and the song book of 1877."
  - Psi Upsilon Letterbook 1877 Volume 1, January - April 1877 (Box 37-4-2060: 1)
    "The correspondence in this volume is largely concerned with the catalogue of 1878 and the preparations for the Convention of 1877 at the Xi."
  - Psi Upsilon Letterbook 1877 Volume 2, May - August 1877 (Box 37-4-2060: 1)
    "The letters in this volume relate chiefly to the Convention of 1877 at the Xi, the midsummer reunion at Auburn, N.Y. in July, and the catalogue of 1878."
- Series II. Manuscripts and notes
  - Manuscript fragments and notes on Arabic transliterations (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Notes on Chaucer in Italy, etc. (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 4)
  - Part I "Chess"- correspondence, notes, articles, etc. (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 10)
  - Part II "Chess" correspondence, notes, articles, etc. (Box 13-1-1165: 15, Folder 11)
  - Notebook - "Fall Trimester 1871-1872 " (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Notebooks and Journals (Box 13-1-348: 18, 26)
  - Notebook - Icelandic (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Manuscript index of photographs (photos not included by referred to by number), annotated in French. When first received by the Cornell Library (ca. 1906?), the photographs indexed were originally assigned Harris call numbers 7851 T13-16: T13 covered Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Russia; T14, the Netherlands, Belgium, and Germany; T15, France; and T16, Italy., 13-1-1165 Bd. Ms. 1
  - Fiske lectures given in Upsala, Sweden, 1851-1852 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 38)
  - Fiske's notebook, bibliographic notes in German (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 52)
- Series III. Petrarch Collection Materials
  - Correspondence regarding the Dante and Petrarch Collections, 1900-1920 (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous material regarding Dante, Petrarch, etc., 1883-1904 (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 2)
  - Letters and bills, 1878, 1881-11903 (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 3-7)
  - Letters and bills (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 8)
  - Sunderland Sale receipts (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 9)
  - Letter from White, H.S. (to Mary Fowler, Cornell University) regarding Petrarch and Dante Collections, 1911-1918 (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 10)
  - I Catalogue of the Petrarch Collection - acknowledgements of gifts (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 11)
  - II Catalogue of the Petrarch Collection - acknowledgements of gifts (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 12)
  - Catalogue of the Petrarch Collection, MSS (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Clarendon Press regarding the Petrarch catalogue, 1914-1917 (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous autographs and contents of Petrarch Rarities (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 15)
  - GW Burr's notes on Petrarch (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 48)
  - Bibliographic notebook with references on Petrarch (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 53)
  - Petrarch and Icelandic autographs (Box 13-1-348: 24, Folder 18)
- Series IV. Dante Collection Materials
  - Dante catalogue correspondence, 1894-1904 (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 16)
  - History of Dante notes, MSS (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 17)
  - Cards and bills (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence of Richard C. Jackson regarding Dante (Box 13-1-1165: 16, Folder 19)
  - Notebook on Dante (Box 13-1-348: 27)
  - Dante bibliography, ca. 1894 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 40)
  - I. Newspaper and magazine articles and illustrations, broadsides, some corres., 1846; 1865-1899
  - II. Same as I., also Poems, 1827; 1831,; 1839,; 1850,; 1861-1903
  - III. Articles concerning the collection of Willard Fiske presented to Cornell University, and about Fiske; corres. concerning Dante Catalogue, 1893-1904
  - IV. Corres. to Kroch, Harris and others from Fiske, 1893-1897; 1899
  - V. Book Reviews; Book announcements; Societies, Conferences, Lectures, etc.; Dramas and Dramatic Presentations, 1880-1915
- Series V. Arabic Material
  - Bundle of Arabic notes (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Bundle of printed materials (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Address book English and Arabic (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Notebooks (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Record book- Exchanges to Libraries (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - "Note on the Italian Words in the Modern Spoken Arabic of Egypt" by Socrates Spiro Bey (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Notes regarding offer of Egyptian Arabic publications (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Letters in envelope - "Letters with D..." from Egypt, including Spiro. Some in Arabiv (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - 2 copies - "Beilage zur Allgemeinen Zeitung", April 26, 1898 (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Article by E.P. Evans on the Arabic Egyptian Alphabet (Box 13-1-1165: 17)
  - Arabic publications (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 58)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous Documents and Memorabilia
  - Pamphlet - Desiderata (2 copies), 1885 (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - v.b. - De Sanctis Francesco, Esposizione critica della Divina Commedia, 1921 (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Address book (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Fiske's "Remarks Introductory to Dante Catalogue, published by Cornell University" (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Fiske's "On the Death of Lincoln" unbound (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Envelope containing copies of photographs of Fiske and frontispiece of "Chess in Iceland" (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Cover of small booklet with page inscribed "Amelia Southworth, Jan. 12, 1841, Earlville" (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Workbook, "Abstracts of History, Pelham Priory, Feb. 13, 1857, Jeannie McGraw" (note spelling) (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Memorial to JMF of poems by Fiske. 1 of 15 copies printed with correspondence enclosed. (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Pamphlet - "J. McG." - 68 copies of memorial poem (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - "The Cornell Magazine" with article on Jennie McGraw Fiske, 1899 (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - "The Florence Gazette", in English, 1890 (Box 13-1-1165: 19)
  - Silver Wreath on Black Pillow, MU-845 (Box 13-1-1165: 21)
    A memorial to Fiske from the Reading Society of the Latin School in Reykjavik (Iceland) called "Ithaka" 1904 (with letter and inscription translation); A small box of Runic coins (22), ca. 1047-1076, and explanatory folder
  - Chair from Willard Fiske's library in Florence, Italy, MU-2129 (Box 13-1-1165)
  - Willard Fiske's suitcase, MU-2130 (Box 13-1-1165)
  - Certain Regulations proposed for Cornell University pamphlets (Box 13-1-348: 17, Folder 4)
  - Fiske calling cards and admission cards (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 36-37)
  - DW Fiske draft statement, Lund, Sweden, September 4, 1852 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 39)
  - Printed poem eulogizing John McGraw, 1877 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 41)
  - Fiske's request for information form, printed (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 49)
  - Notebook on table games in Arabic and other languages (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 50)
  - Fiske's address book, mostly Scandinavian (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 51)
  - Bibliographic notes and addresses, German, 1880 (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 54)
  - Envelopes used for correspondence (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 55)
  - Coat of arms (Box 13-1-348: 19, Folder 56)